Exhibition photographs depicting prominent men in art, law, politics, and government
Prints & Photographs Division, Library of Congress
Exhibition photographs depicting prominent men in art, law, politics, and government ca. 1940-ca. 1965
LOT 13310
Young, Katherine, d. 1993, photographer.
39 photographic prints: gelatin silver; 59 x 48 cm. or smaller
Prints & Photographs Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Formal portraits of national and international figures, including diplomats, statesmen, and political figures.
For information about Prints and Photographs Division collections and services, see the Prints & Photographs Division's Reading Room Home Page.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Young, Katherine, d. 1993, photographer.
Subjects
Architects--1940-1970.; Artists--1940-1970.; Diplomats--1940-1970.; Government officials--1940-1970.; Men--1940-1970.; Politicians--1940-1970.; Statesmen--1940-1970.
Form/Genre
Gelatin silver prints--1940-1970.; Portrait photographs--1940-1970.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift; Katherine Young; 1985 (DLC/PP-1985:197).
Additional Form Available
Digitized images of some items in the collection and their associated identifying information are available through the Prints & Photographs Online Catalog, by searching using the call number "LOT 13310."
Scope and Content Note
Formal portraits of national and international figures. Diplomats, statesmen, and political figures are featured prominently throughout the LOT. Includes some portraits of U.S. Supreme Court justices, architects, and artists. Also one portrait of Alice Acheson.
Organized/Arranged
Portraits arranged in alphabetical order by surname.
http://lccn.loc.gov/99472035
Container List
- Acheson, Alice, LOT 13310, no. 1 (Box 1 of 6)
- Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971, LOT 13310, no. 2
- Adenauer, Konrad, 1876-1967, LOT 13310, no. 3
- Attlee, C.R. (Clement Richard), 1883-1967, LOT 13310, no. 4
- Avery, Milton, 1885-1965, LOT 13310, no. 5
- Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971, LOT 13310, no. 6
- Burton, Harold H. (Harold Hitz), 1888-1964, LOT 13310, no. 7
- Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), 1899-1977, LOT 13310, no. 8 (Box 2 of 6)
- Corbett, Harvey Wiley, 1873-1954, LOT 13310, no. 9
- Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952, LOT 13310, no. 10
- Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-, LOT 13310, no. 11
- Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959, LOT 13310, no. 12
- Erhard, Ludwig, LOT 13310, no. 13
- Franco, Francisco, 1892-1975, LOT 13310, no. 14
- Ismay, Hastings Lionel Ismay, Baron, 1887-1965, LOT 13310, no. 15 (Box 3 of 6)
- Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973, LOT 13310, no. 16
- Jooste, Gerhardus Petrus, LOT 13310, no. 17
- Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974, LOT 13310, no. 18
- Lescaze, William, 1896-1969, LOT 13310, no. 19
- Lewis, John Llewellyn, 1880-1969, LOT 13310, no. 20
- Lie, Trygve, 1896-1968, LOT 13310, no. 21
- Maldarelli, Oronzio, 1892-1962, LOT 13310, no. 22
- Malik, Jacov A., LOT 13310, no. 23 (Box 4 of 6)
- Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954, LOT 13310, no. 24
- Montgomery of Alamein, Bernard Law Montgomery, Viscount, 1887-1976, LOT 13310, no. 25
- Narathipphongpraphan, Prince, grandson of Mongkut, King of Siam, 1891-1976, LOT 13310, no. 26
- Hehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964, LOT 13310, no. 27
- Pandit, V. Laskmi, LOT 13310, no. 28 (Box 5 of 6)
- Pearson, Lester B., LOT 13310, no. 29
- Reed, Stanley Forman, 1884-1980, LOT 13310, no. 30
- Skidmore, Louis, 1897-1962, LOT 13310, no. 31
- Sloan, John, 1871-1951, LOT 13310, no. 32
- Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987, LOT 13310, no. 33
- Sparkman, John, 1899-1985, LOT 13310, no. 34 (Box 6 of 6)
- Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953, LOT 13310, no. 35
- Walker, Ralph, 1889-1973, LOT 13310, no. 36
- Warren, Earl, 1891-1974, LOT 13310, no. 37
- Watkins, Franklin Chenault, 1894-1972, LOT 13310, no. 38
- Weber, Max, 1881-1961, LOT 13310, no. 39